I don't know who I'll be traveling with yet.
모르겠어요 아직 누구와 함께 여행할 예정인지.
They refused to tell me.
그들은 나에게 말하기를 거부했습니다.
I've been wondering who it might be.
누군지 궁금하네요.
The mystery makes this trip that much more thrilling.
수수께끼가 이 여행을 만든다 훨씬 더 스릴있습니다.
It's like something that only happens in movies is happening to me.
그건 그냥 일어나는 일 같아요 영화 속의 일이 나에게 일어나고 있습니다.
Anyway, I'm really nervous but excited.
그나저나 정말 떨리면서도 설렌다.
Hold this. It's warm.
이것을 잡아라. 따뜻해요.
I think the reason every moment
나는 매 순간 이유를 생각한다
of our journey has been beautiful...
우리 여행은 아름다웠어요...
is that you
당신인가요
were a part of the scenery.
풍경의 일부였습니다.
But there's a scene in this movie I like, where they go to the opera.
근데 이 영화에서 제가 좋아하는 장면이 있어요. 오페라를 보러 가는 곳.
Do you know Pretty Woman, the movie with Julia Roberts?
아시나요 예쁜 여인, 줄리아 로버츠가 출연한 영화는요?
Next time, let's go see that opera you memorized.
다음에는 보러가자 당신이 외웠던 그 오페라.
Delicious.
맛있다.
- Mix.
- 믹스.
- Yay, cheers! - Cheers!
- 예, 건배! - 건배!
Beautiful.
아름답다.
So much that I can't look away.
눈을 뗄 수 없을 정도로 많습니다.
I...
나는...
really like you, Cha Mu-hee.
정말 좋아해요, 차무희.
- Wasn't that great? - Yeah.
- 정말 좋지 않았나요? - 응.
That's just the rough cut, but what do you think? Romantic, huh?
그것은 단지 대략적인 컷입니다. 하지만 당신은 어떻게 생각하세요? 로맨틱하죠?
When it comes to on-screen romances,
화면상의 로맨스에 관해서라면,
viewers are used to them, so they don't expect them to be real.
시청자들은 익숙하고 그래서 그들은 그것이 진짜일 것이라고 기대하지 않습니다.
Unless you really start dating and it becomes a story, of course.
진짜 연애를 시작하지 않는 이상 물론 그것은 이야기가 됩니다.
But you aren't dating, are you?
그런데 너 연애하는 거 아니지?
To be frank, it'd be best to broadcast the show as is,
솔직히 말하면 그게 제일 좋겠지만 방송을 그대로 방송하고,
but if this will hurt either of you, we'll edit it.
하지만 이것이 당신 중 누구에게나 상처를 입힐 것이라면, 우리는 그것을 편집할 것입니다.
Sure, we had that bet on the table,
물론이죠, 우리는 테이블에 내기를 걸었습니다.
but we're not thugs who exploit someone's genuine feelings.
하지만 우리는 깡패가 아니야 누군가의 진정한 감정을 이용하는 사람.
It's fine with me. I don't mind.
나는 괜찮아요. 나는 상관하지 않는다.
Did you just... understand what I said?
방금... ​​내가 말한 것을 이해하셨나요?
Yes.
예.
Wow, Hiro! How did you get so good at Korean?
와, 히로! 한국어를 어떻게 그렇게 잘하게 되었나요?
To tell you the truth,
사실대로 말하자면,
I liked you from the second time we ran into each other.
두 번째부터 좋아했어 우리는 서로 마주쳤습니다.
And
그리고
when I found out you were Jin-suk's brother,
내가 그걸 알았을 때 너는 진석의 동생이었어.
I felt a little awkward and embarrassed,
조금 어색하고 부끄러운 느낌이 들었지만,
in case you knew I'd liked you.
내가 당신을 좋아한다는 걸 당신이 알았을까봐.
I was always careful around you.
나는 항상 당신 주위에서 조심했습니다.
In case you'd catch on.
당신이 따라 잡을 경우를 대비해.
Then,
그런 다음,
Ho-jin, did you really like me?
호진아, 나 정말 좋아했니?
I did.
그랬어요.
I never thought the day would come when I'd be telling you this.
그런 날이 올 거라고는 생각도 못했어 내가 당신에게 이것을 말할 때.
Seeing how comfortable I feel telling you,
이렇게 말하니 마음이 편해졌네요.
it seems the zombie movie I thought would never end
좀비영화인거같아 절대 끝나지 않을 줄 알았는데
has finally come to an end, once and for all.
드디어 끝났네요, 단번에.
Zombie movie?
좀비영화?
Two hours until Busan.
부산까지 2시간.
If I'm to clear the air in that time and avoid any misunderstandings,
그 시간에 공기를 맑게 하고 싶다면 그리고 오해를 피하세요.
I'd best start with what happened on Enoshima Island.
무슨 일이 있었는지부터 시작하는 게 좋을 것 같아 에노시마 섬에서.
Right, the photo of you on that island.
그렇죠, 그 섬에서 찍은 사진이요.
Mu-hee took that photo, didn't she?
그 사진은 무희가 찍었죠?
That's right.
좋아요.
That's where I first met her.
내가 그녀를 처음 만난 곳이 바로 그곳이었다.
There, on that day.
거기, 그날.
You said you wanted revenge, so I thought you'd ask them to cut it all.
복수하고 싶다고 했잖아. 그래서 다 잘라달라고 부탁할 줄 알았는데.
Thanks for signing off on it.
승인해 주셔서 감사합니다.
No need to thank me.
나에게 감사할 필요는 없습니다.
That's not how I'll take revenge.
그런 식으로 복수할 생각은 없어요.
Then how will you?
그러면 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
I'm going to stitch you out.
나는 당신을 꿰맬 것입니다.
What?
무엇?
Not that.
그렇지 않습니다.
I'm going to snitch on you.
나는 당신을 밀고 할 것입니다.
About what?
무엇에 대해서?
I'm going to spill the beans about everything.
콩을 쏟을 거에요 모든 것에 대해.
That you hit on me.
당신이 나를 때렸다는 것.
To whom?
누구에게?
You dummy. Who else?
당신은 바보입니다. 또 누구야?
He's great at Japanese, so it'll be easy for me to snitch on you.
그 사람 일본어를 잘하는데, 그러면 내가 당신을 밀고하기가 쉬울 것입니다.
Mr. Joo Ho-jin?
주호진씨요?
Yeah.
응.
He already...
그는 이미...
knows everything.
모든 것을 알고 있습니다.
He does?
그래요?
I told him myself.
나는 그에게 직접 말했다.
I even asked him
나는 심지어 그에게 물었다.
to help me make things work with you.
당신과 함께 일할 수 있도록 도와주세요.
You actually said all that to the guy you like?
사실 다 그렇게 말했잖아 좋아하는 남자한테?
Are you seriously...
당신은 진심으로 ...
Are you stupid?
당신은 바보인가요?
I'm not stupid.
나는 바보가 아니다.
I'm crazy.
나는 미쳤다.
Just think of me as a madwoman like Do Ra-mi.
그냥 나를 미친 여자로 생각해줘 도라미처럼.
I was planning to tease you, but you're no fun.
널 놀릴 생각이었는데, 하지만 넌 재미없어.
Hiro.
히로.
You were dashing.
당신은 대담했습니다.
You were even more dashing on screen.
화면 속에서는 더욱 멋져 보이셨어요.
I know.
알아요.
That's what I thought throughout the entire shoot.
그게 내가 생각한거야 촬영 내내.
How wonderful it would be
얼마나 멋진 일이겠는가?
if dating were nothing but happiness and beautiful views
연애가 행복뿐이라면 그리고 아름다운 전망
with a great guy like you.
너처럼 멋진 남자랑.
Nothing to worry or feel anxious about.
걱정할 것도 없고 불안할 것도 없습니다.
And, at the end of it all, we even had a happy ending.
그리고 결국에는, 우리는 해피엔딩까지 했어요.
I guess that's why Do Ra-mi...
이래서 도라미인가 봐요...
I mean,
내 말은,
why I did that to you.
내가 당신에게 왜 그랬는지.
It's my fault.
내 잘못이야.
I hit on you.
나는 당신을 때렸다.
It was me.
나였어.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
And thank you.
그리고 감사합니다.
You were...
당신은 ...
the prince from my dreams I longed to meet...
내 꿈에 나온 왕자님 만나고 싶었는데...
as an escape from my reality.
내 현실로부터의 도피로서.
Did you get that?
그거 알아냈어?
I don't know. I don't understand.
모르겠습니다. 모르겠어요.
You totally understood!
당신은 완전히 이해했습니다!
You must be a genius. How'd you get fluent in Korean so quickly?
당신은 천재임에 틀림없어요. 어떻게 그렇게 빨리 한국어를 유창하게 할 수 있었나요?
You're awesome.
당신은 정말 대단해요.
When I met you by the clock tower in Italy,
내가 당신을 만났을 때 이탈리아 시계탑 옆에서
and when you asked me if I liked you...
그리고 네가 나한테 너 좋아하냐고 물었을 때...
I've wondered what might have been if I'd just been honest and said yes.
나는 무엇이었을지 궁금했다. 내가 솔직하게 그렇다고 대답했다면.
I regretted not having done so.
그렇게 하지 못한 것을 후회했습니다.
I'm so bitter about that.
나는 그것에 대해 너무 씁쓸합니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I don't understand Japanese at all.
나는 일본어를 전혀 이해하지 못합니다.
You're...
당신은 ...
an idiot.
바보.
What?
무엇?
My mom's here to pick me up, so I'm heading that way.
엄마가 나를 데리러 오셨어 그래서 나는 그쪽으로 가고 있어요.
Okay, I'm going to go catch a cab.
알았어, 택시를 타러 갈 거야.
See you.
또 봐요.
CAN THIS LOVE BE TRANSLATED?
이 사랑을 번역할 수 있나요?
I heard you were looking for a place to donate the antique books
네가 집을 찾고 있다고 들었어 골동품 도서를 기증하기 위해
that belonged to Mr. Yoon Won-jae.
그건 윤원재 씨의 것이었습니다.
I was thinking our university library might be an apt place,
나는 우리 대학 도서관을 생각하고 있었어요 적합한 장소일 수도 있고,
and I was looking into the matter through Mr. Oh.
그리고 난 그 문제를 조사하고 있었어 오씨를 통해서요.
I never imagined you would personally step in, Mr. Kim.
상상도 못했는데 김 선생님이 직접 개입하실 겁니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
- You see-- - Listen.
- 알다시피-- - 들어봐.
I'm not here about that.
나는 그 문제로 여기 온 것이 아닙니다.
I actually came to ask you something about your youngest brother.
사실은 뭐 물어보려고 왔어 네 막내 동생에 대해서.
You came to ask about my brother who died years ago?
당신은 내 동생에 대해 물으러 왔어요 몇 년 전에 누가 죽었나요?
He left behind a daughter, no?
그 사람은 딸을 두고 갔죠, 그렇죠?
Who you adopted.
당신이 입양한 사람.
Is that girl...
그 여자인가...
Ms. Cha Mu-hee?
차무희씨?
Yes, she is.
네, 그렇습니다.
Well, I just thought it was a little odd.
글쎄요, 저는 좀 이상하다고 생각했어요.
Mr. Oh here told me
여기 오씨가 말해줬어요
that he died when he was very young.
그가 아주 어렸을 때 죽었다는 것입니다.
- From a serious illness. - Yes, from a serious illness.
- 심각한 질병에서. - 네, 심각한 질병으로 인해요.
But Ms. Cha Mu-hee said
그런데 차무희씨가 그러더군요.
her parents died in an accident.
그녀의 부모는 사고로 사망했습니다.
Mr. Kim.
김 씨.
Do you know Mu-hee well?
무희님은 잘 아시죠?
Yes, we've crossed paths.
예, 우리는 길을 건너왔습니다.
We dined together and even attended a concert together.
우리는 함께 식사했어요 콘서트도 같이 가봤고.
Right, we both saw her.
맞아, 우리 둘 다 그녀를 봤어.
We were caught between Ms. Cha and Mr. Yoon's grandson.
우리는 차씨 사이에 끼어들었다 그리고 윤씨의 손자.
- Such a cute couple. - That's enough.
- 정말 귀여운 커플이네요. - 그거면 충분해요.
Mr. Yoon's grandson is like a son to me.
윤씨의 손자는 나에게 아들과 같다.
I was just a bit concerned.
다만 조금 걱정이 됐을 뿐입니다.
Goodness, please don't take offense.
맙소사, 화를 내지 마십시오.
If he's like a son to you,
그 사람이 당신에게 아들 같은 존재라면,
please dissuade him from associating with Mu-hee.
그를 설득해 주세요 무희와의 교제에서.
Dissuade him?
그를 설득하시겠습니까?
She may be adopted,
그녀는 입양될 수도 있고,
but isn't Ms. Cha Mu-hee your daughter?
그런데 차무희씨 딸 아니신가요?
We took her in because she's part of our family,
우리는 그녀를 데려갔습니다 그 사람은 우리 가족이니까.
but even we
하지만 우리조차도
didn't want to let that child
그 아이를 놔두고 싶지 않았어
anywhere near us.
우리 근처 어디든.
Yes.
예.
I'm at the station near my place.
나는 내 집 근처 역에 있어요.
But it's so late.
하지만 너무 늦었어요.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
The later the better, what with fewer people around.
늦을수록 좋고, 주변에 사람이 적으니 어쩌겠어요.
Still, it's past midnight.
그런데도 자정이 넘었습니다.
Shouldn't you get to sleep early since you work tomorrow?
일찍 자야 하지 않겠습니까 내일 일하니까?
Mr. Joo Ho-jin, are you tired?
주호진씨 피곤하시죠?
Well, you did work all day and started early.
뭐, 하루 종일 일했잖아 그리고 일찍 시작했다.
You must be pretty tired.
꽤 피곤하시겠군요.
Still, didn't you get some shut-eye on the train?
그래도 눈은 좀 감았지? 기차에서?
Never mind. Sleeping on the train doesn't count as real sleep, does it?
괜찮아요. 기차에서 자고 진짜 잠으로 간주되지 않죠?
If you're tired, you should go home and rest.
피곤하다면, 집에 가서 쉬어야 해.
I slept on the train.
나는 기차에서 잤다.
I'm not tired at all, and thank you for coming to see me.
전혀 피곤하지 않은데, 그리고 나를 보러 와줘서 고마워요.
How did you know? Did you see me?
어떻게 알았나요? 나를 봤어?
You kept rambling, so I figured you were here.
계속 횡설수설하셨어요 그래서 당신이 여기 있는 줄 알았어요.
Well, you were so late getting back.
글쎄, 당신은 너무 늦게 돌아오더군요.
I came here and waited so we wouldn't waste any time.
여기 와서 기다렸어요 그러면 우리는 시간을 낭비하지 않을 것입니다.
Well done.
잘하셨어요.
Your hand is cold.
손이 차갑습니다.
You waited out in the cold,
추운데 밖에서 기다리셨군요.
only to leave?
그냥 떠나려고?
Well,
글쎄,
I didn't tell you I was coming, so I was just going to go.
내가 온다는 말은 안 했는데, 그래서 그냥 가려고 했어요.
Ms. Cha Mu-hee.
차무희씨.
I'm going to spell this out for you, so listen up.
나는 당신을 위해 이것을 철자하겠습니다. 그러니 잘 들어라.
I like you so much
나는 당신을 너무 좋아해요
that I would come see you even after three sleepless nights.
내가 당신을 만나러 올 거라고 삼일 밤을 잠 못 이루고도.
But not four. I might drop dead.
하지만 4개는 아닙니다. 나는 죽을지도 모른다.
Anywhere you want to go?
가고 싶은 곳이 있나요?
There's actually a place I want to show you.
실제로 그런 곳이 있어요 나는 당신에게 보여주고 싶다.
I love this place.
나는 이곳을 좋아한다.
The night view isn't bad, is it?
야경도 나쁘지 않죠?
I just wish we could have seen the stars better.
우리가 볼 수 있었으면 좋았을 텐데 별이 더 좋아.
Do you want to see stars?
별을 보고 싶나요?
I know a great spot for stargazing.
나는 별을 관찰하기에 좋은 장소를 알고 있어요.
Where?
어디?
There's something called the International Dark Sky Association.
이라는 것이 있어요 국제 밤하늘 협회.
Dark Sky Association? That's a thing?
다크스카이협회? 그게 문제야?
They're dedicated to protecting the beauty of the night sky
그들은 보호에 전념하고 있습니다 밤하늘의 아름다움
from light pollution.
빛공해로부터
The first place they designated as a dark-sky preserve in Asia
그들이 지정한 첫 번째 장소 아시아의 밤하늘 보호구역으로
is in Korea.
한국에 있습니다.
Sort of like how the Michelin Guide gives stars to go-to restaurants?
미쉐린 가이드의 방식과 비슷합니다. 가는 레스토랑에 별을 주나요?
Exactly.
정확히.
A go-to spot for stars.
스타들이 자주 찾는 곳.
They say you can see the Milky Way clearly from there.
은하수를 볼 수 있다고 하던데 분명히 거기에서.
The Milky Way?
은하수?
I know about it, but I've never seen it properly.
나는 그것에 대해 알고 하지만 제대로 본 적은 없어요.
- Want to go see it together? - Sure.
- 같이 보러 갈래요? - 확신하는.
We saw the Northern Lights, so let's see the Milky Way too.
우리는 북극광을 보았습니다. 그럼 은하수도 볼까요?
I hope the weather is good. I should collect more clovers.
날씨가 좋기를 바랍니다. 클로버를 더 모아야겠어요.
Sure, do your best.
물론이죠. 최선을 다하세요.
If you think about it,
당신이 그것에 대해 생각한다면,
being taller means you're slightly closer to the sky.
키가 크다는 것은 하늘에 조금 더 가까워졌습니다.
Then I guess you'd have a better view of the stars.
그럼 내 생각엔 별을 더 잘 볼 수 있을 거예요.
No way. Want to check?
안 돼요. 확인하고 싶나요?
Here we go!
간다!
Be careful. So, can you see them better?
조심하세요. 그럼 더 잘 볼 수 있나요?
I can see them much better.
나는 그들을 훨씬 더 잘 볼 수 있습니다.
- All right. Glasses full, ladies? - Sure.
- 괜찮은. 안경이 가득 찼어요, 아가씨들? - 확신하는.
Let's celebrate Shin Ji-sun's broken engagement.
축하하자 신지선 파혼.
- Cheers!
- 건배!
Don't be embarrassed, okay? Better to call it off than end in divorce.
당황하지 마세요, 알았죠? 이혼으로 끝내는 것보다 취소하는 것이 낫습니다.
- Yeah. - What are you saying?
- 응. - 무슨 말이에요?
You could call it off ten times over. It means nothing.
열 번 이상 취소할 수 있습니다. 그것은 아무 의미가 없습니다.
This one here got a divorce.
여기 이 사람은 이혼했어요.
It's fine.
괜찮습니다.
Hey, want me to introduce you to a guy?
저기요, 남자 소개시켜드릴까요?
One of my husband's friends owns a small building in Seoul.
남편 친구 중 한명이 서울에 작은 건물을 소유하고 있습니다.
He's really tall and handsome too.
키도 정말 크고 잘생겼어요.
Wanna meet him?
그를 만나고 싶어?
Forget it. Ji-sun doesn't need us to set her up.
잊어버리세요. 지선이는 우리가 그녀를 설정해 줄 필요가 없습니다.
I'm sure she's surrounded by hot guys all the time.
나는 그녀가 둘러싸여 있다고 확신합니다 항상 섹시한 남자들에 의해.
Ji-sun, date a celebrity next time.
지선아, 다음엔 연예인이랑 데이트해봐.
- Yeah! - A good-looking, older man.
- 응! - 잘생기고 나이 많은 남자.
Don't you girls worry.
걱정하지 마세요.
I already met someone.
나는 이미 누군가를 만났습니다.
- Really?
- 정말?
Yeah!
응!
He's tall, really good-looking, and young.
그는 키가 크고, 정말 잘생겼고, 젊습니다.
He's younger than me.
그는 나보다 어리다.
Shin Ji-sun, you've still got it!
신지선, 아직 남았구나!
- Got any pics? Show us. - Yeah, let's see this young hunk.
- 사진 있어? 우리에게 보여주세요. - 응, 이 젊은 남자 좀 보자.
You wanna see him?
그 사람 보고 싶어?
- Yeah. - Of course.
- 응. - 물론.
I'll show you.
보여드릴게요.
- She's gonna show us. - Let's see him.
- 우리한테 보여줄 거야. - 그 사람 좀 봅시다.
Kim Yong-u?
김용우?
I was looking for him in here, so what's he doing over there?
나는 여기에서 그를 찾고 있었는데, 그럼 그 사람 거기서 뭐하는 거야?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'm the young hunk she's dating.
나는 그 사람이 데이트하고 있는 젊은 남자예요.
He is good-looking.
그 사람은 잘생겼어요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
- Here. - How'd this happen?
- 여기. - 어떻게 된 일이죠?
You said in your text that you were drinking at the market.
당신은 당신의 문자에서 말했다 네가 시장에서 술을 마셨다고.
I searched the whole market.
시장 전체를 검색해 봤습니다.
And why exactly did you come all this way?
그런데 당신은 정확히 왜 여기까지 왔나요?
I came to tell you something important,
중요한 얘기를 하러 왔는데,
and I somehow showed up at the perfect time.
그리고 난 어떻게든 나타났어 완벽한 시간에.
When I told them
내가 그들에게 말했을 때
I broke off my engagement,
약혼을 파기했고,
my friends were trying to comfort me, so I was just showing off a bit.
친구들은 나를 위로하려고 했고, 그래서 그냥 좀 자랑하려고 했어요.
- Showing off. - Right, I see.
- 뽐내고 있어요. - 그렇군요. 알겠습니다.
Still, I'm glad I'm someone you'd want to show off.
그래도 다행이다 나는 당신이 자랑하고 싶은 사람입니다.
Thanks.
감사해요.
So what did you want to tell me?
그럼 나한테 무슨 말을 하고 싶었던 거야?
Ms. Shin Ji-sun.
신지선씨.
Will you
당신은
marry me?
나랑 결혼해?
What?
무엇?
Let's get married.
결혼하자.
What are you waiting for?
당신은 무엇을 기다리고 있습니까?
Ji-sun, what are you waiting for? Say yes!
지선아, 뭘 기다리고 있어? 네 라고 말하다!
Go on, say yes!
어서 예라고 말하세요!
- Guys, cut it out! - Say yes!
- 얘들아, 그만해! - 응이라고 말해!
- Please!
- 제발!
Say yes!
네 라고 말하다!
I know it was out of nowhere, but I couldn't think of any other option.
갑자기 일어난 일이라는 걸 알아요 하지만 다른 선택지는 생각나지 않았어요.
Because I never want us to break up.
난 우리가 헤어지는 걸 절대 원하지 않으니까.
Who said we're breaking up?
누가 우리 헤어지자고 했어?
I'm going to the UK to work for a sports agency.
나는 영국에 갈거야 스포츠 에이전시에서 일하기 위해.
I even met my new client.
나는 심지어 새로운 고객을 만났습니다.
It's always been my dream, so I can't give it up,
항상 내 꿈이었어, 그래서 포기할 수 없어요.
but I can't leave without you.
하지만 나는 당신 없이는 떠날 수 없습니다.
What, you think I'll cheat on you if you're not around?
뭐야, 내가 널 속일 것 같아? 만약 당신이 주변에 없다면?
Would you really?
정말 그럴까요?
I won't ask you to come with me, so just marry me.
나는 당신에게 나와 함께 가자고 요청하지 않을 것입니다. 그러니 그냥 나랑 결혼해.
I won't.
나는하지 않을 것이다.
Getting married won't be necessary.
결혼은 필요하지 않을 것이다.
Instead, let's go together.
대신 같이 가자.
After the show, I was planning to take a year off to study.
공연이 끝난 후 계획을 세웠는데 1년을 쉬고 공부하려고요.
I'd planned it while preparing for the wedding,
내가 계획했을 텐데 결혼식을 준비하면서,
and even after calling off the engagement, I was going to stick to the plan.
그리고 약혼을 취소한 뒤에도 나는 그 계획을 고수하기로 했다.
I had planned to study in the US, but I can just go to a different country.
미국 유학을 계획하고 있었는데, 하지만 다른 나라로 갈 수는 있어요.
And you hadn't told me?
그리고 나한테 말하지 않았나요?
I'd been hesitating because of you.
당신 때문에 망설이고 있었어요.
I thought maybe I should give up on my plan,
아마도 계획을 포기해야 하는데,
but then wondered if I was getting ahead of myself...
그런데 궁금해졌다 내가 나보다 앞서갔더라면...
Thank you for hesitating for my sake.
저를 위해 망설여주셔서 감사합니다.
I caught your strong dialect earlier. I was impressed.
아까 당신의 강한 사투리를 알아냈어요. 나는 감동받았다.
I speak two languages.
나는 두 가지 언어를 구사합니다.
My mom's Busan dialect and Dad's Seoul dialect.
우리 엄마 부산 사투리 그리고 아빠의 서울 사투리.
What about English?
영어는 어떻습니까?
You seemed pretty fluent last time.
지난번에는 꽤 유창하게 보이던데요.
Gee...
이런...
H...
하...
I sleep well these days even without meds, and I don't see Do Ra-mi.
요즘은 약 없이도 잘 자는데, 그리고 도라미가 안 보여요.
But I wonder why I don't see Do Ra-mi anymore.
그런데 궁금해요 왜 도라미가 더 이상 보이지 않는지.
I've given it some thought,
좀 생각해봤는데,
and I shared a lifelong secret with someone I deeply rely on.
그리고 나는 평생의 비밀을 공유했습니다 내가 깊이 의지하는 사람과 함께.
I think that might be why.
그 이유가 아닐까 싶습니다.
What kind of secret was it?
어떤 비밀이 있었나요?
It's about my childhood.
그것은 내 어린 시절에 관한 것입니다.
Then perhaps Do Ra-mi is related to your childhood, Ms. Cha Mu-hee.
그렇다면 도라미가 관련이 있는 건 아닐까. 당신의 어린시절을, 차무희씨.
Do Ra-mi couldn't have existed when I was a kid.
도라미는 존재할 수 없었을 것이다 내가 어렸을 때.
Perhaps you only thought it was Do Ra-mi
아마 도라미만 생각했을 거에요
because your symptoms began after filming that movie.
증상이 시작되었기 때문에 그 영화를 찍고 나서요.
Was the person you were seeing
당신이 만나고 있던 사람이었나?
really Do Ra-mi?
정말 도라미?
I was sure it was Do Ra-mi, but he said it might not be her.
확실히 도라미인 줄 알았는데, 하지만 그는 그녀가 아닐 수도 있다고 말했습니다.
Didn't she tell you herself that she was Do Ra-mi?
그녀가 직접 말하지 않았나요? 도라미였다고?
She said everything came from your own head.
그녀는 모든 것이 왔다고 말했다 당신 자신의 머리에서.
Maybe she said that because it's what you believed.
어쩌면 그녀가 그렇게 말했을지도 몰라 왜냐하면 당신이 믿었던 것이기 때문입니다.
She looked like me, was terrifying,
그녀는 나와 닮았고, 무서웠습니다.
and kept criticizing me. Naturally, I thought she was Do Ra-mi.
저를 계속 비난했어요. 당연히 도라미인 줄 알았어요.
Are you still at the hospital?
아직도 병원에 계시나요?
No, I'm shopping for Yong-u's present.
아니요, 용우 씨 선물을 쇼핑 ​​중이에요.
I feel like I'm sending away my baby brother.
보내주는 것 같아 내 동생.
- Are you at home, Ho-jin? - Yes.
- 호진아 집에 있어? - 예.
I'm waiting for a guest.
손님을 기다리고 있어요.
A guest?
손님?
The novelist?
소설가?
No.
아니요.
I'll tell you about it next time.
이에 대해서는 다음번에 말씀드리겠습니다.
What do you mean "next time"? See you this evening.
"다음에"는 무슨 뜻인가요? 오늘 저녁에 뵙겠습니다.
Perhaps you didn't emerge due to a rapid change in her environment
아마도 당신은 나타나지 않았을 것입니다 급격한 환경 변화로 인해
but from a much deeper
하지만 훨씬 더 깊은 곳에서
and darker past.
그리고 더 어두운 과거.
Do you have this in a larger size?
이거 더 큰 사이즈 있나요?
- Sure, let me check for you. - Thank you.
- 물론이죠. 확인해 보겠습니다. - 감사합니다.
Picking out a present?
선물을 고르시나요?
I heard that Mr. Yoon had quite a formidable collection,
윤씨한테 들었는데 꽤 어마어마한 컬렉션을 보유하고 있었고,
but seeing it in person,
하지만 직접 보면
it's even more impressive than I imagined.
상상했던 것보다 훨씬 더 인상적이에요.
I heard you had something you insisted on telling me in person.
너한테 뭔가 있다고 들었어 당신은 나에게 직접 말하겠다고 고집했습니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
First, I wanted to ask you to consider donating to our foundation.
먼저, 나는 당신에게 묻고 싶었습니다. 우리 재단에 기부하는 것을 고려해 보세요.
Everything here is my mother's. It's not mine to give away.
여기 있는 모든 것은 우리 어머니 것이에요. 내어주는 것은 내 것이 아닙니다.
It seems Mu-hee has given you an unfavorable impression of us.
무희가 준 것 같아 우리에 대한 좋지 않은 인상.
I wonder just how terribly you treated her to assume that right away.
당신이 그녀를 얼마나 끔찍하게 대했는지 궁금해요 바로 그것을 가정하는 것입니다.
We were fairly strict with her.
우리는 그녀에게 상당히 엄격했습니다.
She's a cunning girl, apt at telling lies depending on the circumstances.
그녀는 교활하고 거짓말을 잘하는 여자야 상황에 따라.
Sounds like she was a clever person who caught on fast
그 사람 똑똑한 사람이었던 것 같은데 누가 빨리 잡았어?
to the fact that she could never be honest in a place shrouded by lies.
그녀는 결코 솔직할 수 없다는 사실에 거짓말로 뒤덮인 곳에서.
You pretended to be selfless as a child,
넌 어렸을 때 이타적인 척을 했고,
but now that you're somewhat famous, you seem to want things out of your reach.
하지만 이제 어느 정도 유명해졌으니 당신은 손이 닿지 않는 곳에 물건을 원하는 것 같습니다.
I'm not just somewhat famous.
나는 단지 다소 유명한 것이 아닙니다.
I've earned so much money
나는 돈을 너무 많이 벌었어요
that these things are well within my reach.
이런 것들이 내 손이 닿는 곳에 있어요.
Now you're the very image of her.
이제 당신은 그녀의 이미지입니다.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Your uncle has gone to meet the maternal grandson of Mr. Yoon Won-jae.
삼촌이 만나러 가셨어 윤원재 씨의 외손자.
We had no choice but to tell him about you.
우리에게는 선택의 여지가 없었다 하지만 그에게 당신에 대해 말하려고요.
His family could be of great help to us.
그의 가족은 우리에게 큰 도움이 될 수 있습니다.
Don't try to own things that don't suit you
물건을 소유하려고 하지 마세요 그건 너한테 어울리지 않아
simply because things are starting to look up for you.
단순히 일이 시작되고 있기 때문에 당신을 찾기 위해.
Aunt.
이모.
The woman who gave birth to Mu-hee was not family.
무희를 낳은 여자 가족은 아니었어요.
My brother never married that woman.
내 동생은 그 여자와 결혼한 적이 없어요.
She tried to use that child to stop him from leaving her.
그 아이를 이용하려고 했어 그가 그녀를 떠나는 것을 막기 위해.
And when that didn't work out like she'd hoped,
그리고 그게 잘 안 됐을 때 그녀가 바라던 대로,
she caused a huge tragedy in an attempt to ruin everything.
그녀는 엄청난 비극을 일으켰다 모든 것을 망치려는 시도.
That's the kind of mother she had.
그녀에게는 그런 어머니가 있었습니다.
It's a shameful part of our history
우리 역사의 부끄러운 부분이다
that we wanted to keep hidden.
우리가 숨기고 싶었던 것.
I heard you were quite close to her.
당신이 그 사람과 꽤 친하다고 들었어요.
I requested to meet because I had to share this with you.
만나자고 했어요 왜냐하면 이 사실을 여러분과 공유해야 했기 때문입니다.
If that were the case, you shouldn't have come all this way.
만약 그랬다면, 당신은 이리까지 오지 말았어야 했어요.
Mu-hee already told me everything.
무희는 이미 나에게 모든 것을 말해주었다.
She told you about herself?
그녀가 당신 자신에 대해 말했나요?
He already knows. I told him everything.
그는 이미 알고 있습니다. 나는 그에게 모든 것을 말했습니다.
You told him?
당신이 그에게 말했어요?
I told him. Everything.
나는 그에게 말했다. 모든 것.
Everything?
모든 것?
I knew it.
나는 그것을 알고 있었다.
So you do remember what happened to your parents that day.
그러니까 기억나지? 그날 네 부모님은 무슨 일이 있었는지.
I was simply terrified.
나는 단지 겁이 났을 뿐이다.
I told you I didn't remember because I was scared you'd kick me out.
내가 기억나지 않는다고 말했잖아 왜냐하면 당신이 나를 쫓아낼까봐 두려웠기 때문입니다.
I remember everything.
나는 모든 것을 기억합니다.
Happy birthday, Mu-hee.
무희야, 생일 축하해
Mu-hee.
무희.
You should eat some too.
너도 좀 먹어야 해.
Let's all be happy together.
모두 함께 행복해지자.
That woman laced her daughter's birthday cake with poison
끈 묶인 저 여자 독이 든 딸의 생일 케이크
and tried to die with her.
그리고 그녀와 함께 죽으려고 했어요.
Perhaps the girl refused and tried to run
아마도 그 소녀는 거절하고 도망치려 했을 것이다.
because she fell off the balcony.
왜냐하면 그녀가 발코니에서 떨어졌기 때문이죠.
She said she had no memories of that horrid incident,
기억이 없다고 하더군요 그 끔찍한 사건에 대해,
which we thought was a relief.
우리는 안도감을 느꼈다고 생각했습니다.
You turned your back on her.
당신은 그녀에게 등을 돌렸습니다.
Ever since she was a child,
그녀는 어렸을 때부터
Ms. Cha Mu-hee has carried the weight of those awful memories
차무희씨가 가지고 오신 그 끔찍한 기억의 무게
entirely on her own.
전적으로 혼자서.
I pitied her, yes, but she was her daughter.
나는 그녀를 불쌍히 여겼다. 하지만 그녀는 그녀의 딸이었습니다.
She made our skin crawl.
그녀는 우리의 피부를 크롤링하게 만들었습니다.
There's only one photo I didn't destroy.
제가 훼손하지 않은 사진은 단 한 장뿐입니다.
I intended to show it to Mu-hee if she ever brought up her mom.
무희한테 보여주려고 했는데 그녀가 엄마를 키운 적이 있다면.
See for yourself why we find that girl so terrifying.
직접 확인해보세요 우리가 그 여자를 그렇게 무섭게 생각하는 이유.
It wasn't my fault.
내 잘못이 아니었어요.
So why did you
그럼 왜 그랬어?
hate me so much?
내가 그렇게 싫어?
We were afraid.
우리는 두려웠습니다.
We were so afraid of you.
우리는 당신을 너무 두려워했습니다.
If you remember,
기억하신다면,
you must also remember your mom.
너도 엄마를 기억해야 해.
Then again,
그럼 다시,
there's no way you couldn't.
그러지 못할 리가 없어요.
Seeing that face in the mirror every day,
매일 거울 속의 그 얼굴을 보며
you couldn't possibly forget your mom.
넌 엄마를 잊을 수 없을 거야.
Mom.
엄마.
She looked like me, was terrifying, and kept criticizing me.
그녀는 나와 닮았고, 무서웠어요. 계속 저를 비난했어요.
Naturally, I thought she was Do Ra-mi.
당연히 도라미인 줄 알았어요
If that face wasn't Do Ra-mi's, then whose could it be?
그 얼굴이 도라미의 얼굴이 아니었다면, 그렇다면 누구일까요?
It was my mom.
우리 엄마였어요.
Do Ra-mi
도라미
had my mom's face.
엄마 얼굴을 하고 있었어요.
At last, you recognize me.
마침내 당신은 나를 알아보았습니다.
Here.
여기.
Let's all be happy now.
이제 우리 모두 행복해지자.
You should eat some too.
너도 좀 먹어야 해.
I don't want to.
나는 원하지 않는다.
The chicks died after eating the cake.
병아리들은 케이크를 먹은 후 죽었습니다.
And Dad too.
그리고 아빠도요.
You want to be left behind all alone?
혼자 남겨지고 싶나요?
Why?
왜?
There would be no one
아무도 없을 텐데
left in this world to love you.
당신을 사랑하기 위해 이 세상에 남겨졌습니다.
You could never be happy.
당신은 결코 행복할 수 없습니다.
I still don't want it.
나는 아직도 그것을 원하지 않는다.
Mom.
엄마.
That day,
그날
I never fully managed to get away from my mom.
완전히 관리한 적이 없습니다. 엄마에게서 벗어나려고요.
Her words that I'd never be happy
나는 절대 행복하지 않을 거라는 그녀의 말
kept coming back to me, no matter how hard I tried to erase them,
계속 나에게 돌아왔고, 아무리 지우려고 해도
and haunted me my entire life.
평생 나를 괴롭혔습니다.
So this time, I must use all I have
그래서 이번에는 내가 가진 모든 것을 사용해야 합니다
to try once more
한 번 더 시도해 보세요
to truly break free from this delusion.
이러한 망상에서 진정으로 벗어나고자 합니다.
Please try your darndest
최선을 다해 시험해 보세요
so I can finally get lost.
그래서 결국 길을 잃을 수 있어요.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
Ms. Cha Mu-hee.
Ms. 차무희.
I love you.
사랑해요.
Ms. Cha Mu-hee, are you with us?
차무희씨, 같이 계세요?
You were out for three days. I was so worried, Mu-hee.
당신은 3일 동안 밖에 있었어요. 너무 걱정했어요, 무희.
I thought you'd be out for a while, like last time.
난 당신이 한동안 밖에 있을 줄 알았는데, 지난번처럼.
Hey, I'm fine.
안녕, 난 괜찮아.
Even the doctor said I'm fine.
의사 선생님도 괜찮다고 하더군요.
I contacted Mr. Joo.
주씨에게 연락했어요.
He's on his way, so he should be here soon.
그 사람 지금 가는 중이야 그러니 그 사람이 곧 여기에 올 거에요.
He will?
그 사람이 그럴까요?
Hey, give me a mirror. I haven't washed my hair.
야, 거울 좀 줘 나는 머리를 씻지 않았습니다.
I guess you're back.
당신이 돌아온 것 같아요.
Thank goodness.
맙소사.
It would've killed Mr. Joo otherwise.
그렇지 않았다면 주씨를 죽였을 것이다.
He couldn't stay here,
그는 여기에 머물 수 없었습니다.
what with all the reporters and the show's crew visiting.
기자들 다 어쩌고 그리고 쇼의 제작진이 방문합니다.
He was withering away at home, unable to sleep.
그는 집에서 시들고 있었고, 잠을 잘 수 없습니다.
Hiro!
히로!
Ms. Cha Mu-hee is awake.
차무희씨가 깨어있습니다.
Really? Is she okay?
정말? 그 사람 괜찮아요?
I spoke to Mr. Kim Yong-u on the phone, and he said she's well.
김용우씨와 통화를 했는데, 그리고 그는 그녀가 괜찮다고 말했습니다.
I knew it.
나는 그것을 알고 있었다.
There's no way a zombie would die so easily.
방법이 없어요 좀비는 너무 쉽게 죽을 것입니다.
Oh no. I'm exhausted.
안 돼. 나는 지쳤다.
Hey, are you okay?
이봐, 괜찮아?
You've spent three days going at it with that punching bag.
당신은 3일을 보냈습니다. 그 샌드백을 가지고 가죠.
I was worried you might collapse too.
너도 쓰러질까봐 걱정됐어.
I won't collapse from this!
나는 이것으로 무너지지 않을 것이다!
Take this off. I don't have the strength to do it myself.
이것을 벗어라. 나는 그것을 스스로 할 힘이 없습니다.
Your hands are trembling.
손이 떨리고 있습니다.
- I'm fine. - You shouldn't overexert yourself.
- 잘 지내요. - 무리한 노력을 하시면 안됩니다.
This is all that zombie's fault.
이게 다 그 좀비의 잘못이에요.
When I see her, I'm going to get my revenge.
내가 그녀를 볼 때, 나는 복수를 할 것이다.
Why are you always going on about revenge?
왜 맨날 복수하려고 하는 거야?
We really do look alike.
우리는 정말 닮았어요.
She's not the same person as you, Ms. Cha Mu-hee. Not at all.
그 사람은 너랑 같은 사람이 아니야 차무희씨. 별말씀을요.
I know.
알아요.
Mu-hee.
무희.
There's something you still don't know.
당신이 아직 모르는 것이 있습니다.
That day,
그날,
on your birthday,
당신의 생일에,
someone reported that a child had fallen,
어떤 사람이 아이가 넘어졌다고 신고했어요.
so the police entered your home.
그래서 경찰이 당신 집에 들이닥쳤어요.
Thanks to that, your parents were found and saved.
그 덕분에 너희 부모님이 발견되어 구원받았느니라.
Then...
그럼...
They're still alive.
그들은 아직 살아있습니다.
The father you thought had passed away was actually your youngest uncle.
세상을 떠났다고 생각했던 아버지 사실은 막내 삼촌이었어요.
So your father
그럼 네 아버지는
is actually your uncle who lives abroad.
사실은 외국에 사는 삼촌이에요.
I had no idea.
나는 전혀 몰랐다.
Even as a kid, I didn't get to see my dad very often,
어린 시절에도, 아버지를 자주 만나지 못했는데,
so I had no idea what he looked like.
그래서 나는 그가 어떻게 생겼는지 전혀 몰랐습니다.
Apparently, no one knows the whereabouts of your mother since the incident,
아무래도 행방을 아는 사람은 아무도 없을 것 같다 그 사건 이후로 당신 어머니의
but she's definitely alive.
하지만 그녀는 확실히 살아 있어요.
Then why did they tell me...
그럼 그 사람들은 왜 나한테 말했지...
that both of them died that day?
그날 둘 다 죽었다고?
You said you didn't remember the incident,
그 사건을 기억하지 못한다고 하셨는데,
so they covered up the events of that day.
그래서 그들은 그 날의 사건을 은폐했습니다.
Your father's family deceived you.
당신 아버지의 가족이 당신을 속였습니다.
So they were alive.
그래서 그들은 살아있었습니다.
I desperately wanted to join this project, so I shot that in a hurry.
나는 이 프로젝트에 꼭 참여하고 싶었고, 그래서 급하게 찍었어요.
Thank you for your kind words.
당신의 친절한 말에 감사드립니다.
I prepared some words to say on my own, without an interpreter.
제가 직접 할 말을 준비했는데, 통역사 없이.
You've changed, Hiro.
당신은 변했어요, 히로.
You've matured.
당신은 성숙했습니다.
Your father said he couldn't bear to see you,
네 아버지가 말씀하셨지 그 사람은 당신을 보고 싶어 견딜 수가 없었어요
so we had no choice but to take you in.
그래서 우리는 당신을 받아들일 수밖에 없었습니다.
I'm not here to blame you.
나는 당신을 비난하기 위해 여기 있는 것이 아닙니다.
I came to ask you for a favor.
나는 당신에게 부탁을 하러 왔습니다.
The only one who can find out where my mom is now
알아낼 수 있는 유일한 사람 우리 엄마는 지금 어디에 계시나요
is, in the end,
는 결국,
my father, who was closest to her.
그녀와 가장 가까운 아버지.
Please ask that man...
그 사람한테 물어보세요...
to at least find that out for me.
적어도 나한테는 그걸 알아주려고.
You're going to meet your mom?
엄마를 만나러 갈 거야?
I need to see that she's alive with my own two eyes.
그 사람이 살아있는지 확인해야 해요 내 두 눈으로.
I think it's the only way to be truly free of her.
내 생각엔 그게 유일한 방법인 것 같아 그녀에게서 진정으로 자유로워지기 위해.
All right.
괜찮은.
I have to say I'm a little worried.
조금 걱정스럽다고 해야 할까요.
Don't you worry.
걱정하지 마세요.
There's always Papago.
항상 파파고가 있습니다.
And it's Koreatown, so I won't even need to use Papago.
그리고 코리아타운이에요. 그래서 나는 Papago를 사용할 필요조차 없을 것이다.
I could go with you, you know.
나도 당신과 함께 갈 수 있어요.
Not as an interpreter, but just as moral support.
통역사가 아닌, 그러나 도덕적 지원과 마찬가지로.
Mr. Joo Ho-jin.
주호진 씨.
I told myself
나는 나 자신에게 말했다
that we'll never have a happy ending.
우리는 결코 행복한 결말을 맞이할 수 없을 것입니다.
So you, not wanting me to be anxious,
그래서 당신은 내가 불안해지기를 바라지 않고,
said all that nonsense about how it's fine 'cause we'll definitely break up.
괜찮다는 헛소리를 했어 왜냐면 우리는 분명히 헤어질 테니까.
I don't want us to definitely break up.
우리가 꼭 헤어지는 걸 원하지 않아요.
So let's...
그럼...
break up right here this time.
이번에는 여기서 헤어지세요.
I'll come back and threaten you into dating me again.
다시 와서 협박할게 나랑 다시 데이트하자고.
When I do,
내가 할 때,
please give in so we can be happy together for a very long time.
우리가 함께 행복할 수 있도록 양보해주세요 아주 오랫동안.
I'm not one to give in to threats.
나는 위협에 굴복할 사람이 아니다.
You'd better come prepared and bring your worst.
준비해서 오시는 게 좋을 것 같아요 그리고 최악의 상황을 가져오세요.
I will.
그럴게요.
I wonder how she's doing.
그녀는 어떻게 지내는지 궁금해요.
Can I pack some of your gochujang to bring to the UK?
고추장 좀 포장해도 될까요? 영국으로 데려가려고?
Your housekeeper makes it so well.
집사님이 너무 잘 만드시네요.
Sure. Take some.
확신하는. 좀 가져가세요.
Hey, Mr. Joo.
안녕하세요, 주 씨.
Can I take some soy sauce too?
간장도 좀 먹어도 될까요?
Go on.
계속하세요.
Where was it again?
또 어디였지?
Under the sink...
싱크대 밑...
- The sink? - I'll find it for you.
- 싱크대요? - 제가 찾아드릴게요.
No, it's okay.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
Why did he bring that pot in from outside...
저 사람은 왜 밖에서 그 냄비를 가지고 들어왔는지...
- Found it? - Found it.
- 찾았나요? - 찾았어요.
- A container... - Take it.
- 컨테이너... - 받아요.
- Mr. Joo, I-- - Just take it all!
- 주 선생님, 저는-- - 그냥 다 가져가세요!
All of it.
모든 것.
Ji-sun's rubbing off on you in all sorts of weird ways.
지선이가 널 비비고 있어 온갖 이상한 방법으로.
Why did you bring this bag here?
이 가방을 왜 여기로 가져왔나요?
Give them to me.
나에게 주세요.
I'll be donating my father's books to the university library,
나는 아버지의 책을 기증할 것이다 대학 도서관으로,
but let's think about what to do with the other antiques and paintings.
하지만 어떻게 해야할지 생각해 보자 다른 골동품과 그림과 함께.
Can't you deal with them all while you're here?
다 처리할 수는 없나요? 당신이 여기 있는 동안?
Hey, those are all invaluable pieces. I can't sort through them all in one go.
아, 그거 다 귀중한 작품이군요. 한 번에 다 정리할 수가 없어요.
I'll take my time with it over several visits.
나는 그것에 시간을 할애할 것이다 여러 번의 방문에 걸쳐
And keep using this house as a storage unit?
그리고 이 집을 계속 이용하세요 저장 장치로?
Why?
왜?
Do you want to sell this house and buy an apartment for marriage?
이 집을 팔고 싶나요? 결혼을 위해 아파트를 사시나요?
Hey.
여기요.
Can I have this book?
이 책을 가질 수 있나요?
- It's yours. - Really?
- 그것은 당신 것입니다. - 정말?
Then
그런 다음
how about this one?
이건 어때요?
As you wish.
당신이 원하는대로.
That's a first edition Dickens.
디킨스의 초판입니다.
Oh my, not the Dickens.
아, 디킨스는 아니군요.
- Just let me have it. - I'll take that.
- 그냥 나한테 맡겨줘. - 내가 가져갈게.
Hey, no take-backs!
이봐, 반품은 안돼!
- Why have you gotten so greedy? - You wouldn't even take good care of them!
- 왜 이렇게 욕심이 났나요? - 당신은 그들을 잘 돌보지도 않을 거예요!
I will.
그럴게요.
Hold up!
잠깐만요!
First, you toy with someone's heart, and now you're doing the same with a book.
첫째, 누군가의 마음을 가지고 장난을 치고, 이제 당신은 책을 가지고 같은 일을 하고 있습니다.
Sell this house and move...
이 집 팔고 이사가세요...
But Ms. Cha Mu-hee liked this house.
그런데 차무희 씨는 이 집이 마음에 들었다.
This year, we're all celebrating New Year's Eve together.
올해는 우리 모두 축하해요 설날을 함께합니다.
You'll join us, won't you?
당신도 우리와 함께 할 건가요?
- Sure. - We'll be expecting you.
- 확신하는. - 우리는 당신을 기다리고 있습니다.
So the whole gang is coming this time?
그럼 이번에는 일행 전체가 오는 건가요?
Of course. Everyone will be there.
물론. 모두가 거기에 있을 것이다.
Can't you bring your girlfriend with you?
여자친구를 데리고 갈 수는 없나요?
I can't.
나는 할 수 없다.
We're broken up right now.
우리는 지금 헤어진 상태입니다.
Come on. You got dumped again?
어서 해봐요. 또 버림받았나요?
I'm off.
나는 떠난다.
Hey, it's okay if you're late, so join us instead of staying home alone.
야, 늦어도 괜찮아 그러니 집에 혼자 있지 말고 우리와 함께 하세요.
- Okay. - Bye.
- 좋아요. - 안녕.
You're the absolute best.
당신은 절대적으로 최고입니다.
Everyone!
모든 사람!
Today's the day
오늘이 바로 그날이다
we submitted the final cut of Romantic Trip!
우리는 최종 컷을 제출했습니다 낭만여행!
We almost missed the deadline. The penalty is a couple hundred million.
우리는 마감일을 거의 놓쳤습니다. 벌금은 몇억입니다.
My hands were trembling as I was typing out the captions.
손이 떨리고 있었어요 내가 캡션을 입력하는 동안.
You'd better toughen up a little.
좀 더 강해지는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Once it airs and the ratings are in, your whole body will be shaking.
방송되고 시청률이 나오면 온 몸이 떨릴 것이다.
Oh, come on...
아, 어서...
I'm not worried. Our show's great.
나는 걱정하지 않는다. 우리 쇼는 정말 훌륭해요.
Of course you're not worried.
물론 걱정하지 않으셔도 됩니다.
You're running away to the UK before the numbers come out.
당신은 영국으로 도망가고 있어요 숫자가 나오기 전에.
She's right.
그녀 말이 맞아요.
- Hey, what's that? - What's that?
- 야, 그게 뭐야? - 그게 뭐죠?
Which is why I'm buying tonight.
그래서 오늘 밤에 구매하려고 합니다.
Despite the producer changing partway through filming,
프로듀서가 바뀌었음에도 불구하고 촬영 중간에,
you all did a great job.
여러분 모두 훌륭한 일을 했습니다.
- Shall we raise a glass? - Let's raise a glass!
- 잔을 들어볼까요? - 잔을 들어보자!
Hello, everyone!
여러분, 안녕하세요!
- Welcome. - Hey, you're here!
- 환영. - 야, 왔구나!
I heard you turned in the cut. Good work, all.
당신이 컷을 제출했다고 들었습니다. 모두 잘했어요.
It was nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니었습니다.
Our show is going to be a huge hit. You know that, right?
우리 쇼는 큰 인기를 끌 것입니다. 그거 알지?
Our company card. Today's on me.
우리 회사 카드. 오늘은 나에게 달려있다.
- Okay! - Wow!
- 좋아요! - 우와!
Hey, so you show up like this out of nowhere?
야, 그래서 이렇게 나타나다니 갑자기?
Man, I was so shocked.
아저씨, 너무 충격받았어요.
You're going to ride on our coattails?
우리 코트 테일을 탈 건가요?
He'll start with the tails, then just wear the coat.
그는 꼬리부터 시작할 거예요. 그럼 그냥 코트를 입으세요.
Didn't you see this coming? This is how Producer Kim plays the game.
이게 오는 걸 못 봤나요? 김 PD가 게임을 하는 방식은 이렇다.
- Right. - Merry Christmas!
- 오른쪽. - 메리 크리스마스!
Thanks for dinner!
저녁 식사 감사합니다!
Babe.
자기야.
Want to go see the stars with me?
나와 함께 별 보러 갈래?
What a succinct but effective threat.
얼마나 간결하지만 효과적인 위협입니까?
Welcome, and thank you for visiting our observatory.
환영합니다, 감사합니다 우리 천문대를 방문해주셔서 감사합니다.
The International Dark Sky Association,
국제밤하늘협회
dedicated to protecting the night sky from artificial light,
밤하늘을 지키기 위해 헌신합니다 인공 조명으로부터
certified this site as Asia's first dark-sky preserve.
이 사이트를 인증함 아시아 최초의 밤하늘 보호구역입니다.
Here, you can observe celestial wonders like the Milky Way
여기서 천상의 경이로움을 관찰할 수 있습니다 은하수처럼
and shooting stars with the naked eye.
육안으로 볼 수 있는 별똥별
As the lights go out and darkness settles in,
불이 꺼지면서 어둠이 찾아오고,
the stars will begin to appear one by one.
별이 하나씩 나타나기 시작합니다.
We hope you have an unforgettable night here
당신이 그랬기를 바랍니다 여기서 잊지 못할 밤을 보내세요
at our observatory with someone special.
특별한 누군가와 함께 천문대에서
Have you come to see the stars?
별을 보러 오셨나요?
You need to do a good job interpreting today.
일을 잘해야 해 오늘은 통역.
He might be really mad at me because I took so long.
그 사람 나한테 정말 화났을지도 몰라 너무 오래 걸렸거든요.
Please translate with all your heart.
성심껏 번역해 주십시오.
I've missed you.
나는 당신을 그리워했습니다.
I guess English doesn't work on him.
아무래도 그 사람에게는 영어가 통하지 않는 것 같아요.
Let's try Japanese.
일본어를 시도해 봅시다.
I really missed you.
정말 보고 싶었어요.
Does he still not understand me?
그 사람 아직도 내 말을 이해 못 하는 걸까?
I missed you so much.
나는 당신을 너무 보고 싶었습니다.
So much that it almost killed me.
너무 많아서 거의 죽을 뻔했습니다.
Why aren't you reacting? You understood everything.
왜 반응이 없나요? 당신은 모든 것을 이해했습니다.
Why aren't you saying anything back?
왜 아무 말도 안 해요?
Are you really mad at me?
너 정말 나한테 화났어?
I was having trouble finding the right words to reply with.
나는 어려움을 겪고 있었다 대답할 적절한 단어를 찾는 것.
"Have you come to see the stars?"
"별 보러 오셨나요?"
I even brought a bouquet of clovers...
클로버 꽃다발도 가져왔는데..
so that we'd have clear skies.
맑은 하늘을 가질 수 있도록 말이죠.
If you're mad at me, you can swear at me.
나한테 화나면 욕해도 돼요.
If you'd rather not talk,
차라리 말을 하지 않으려면,
you can use a universal language.
보편적인 언어를 사용할 수 있습니다.
Sure.
확신하는.
That option
해당 옵션
seems most appropriate.
가장 적절해 보입니다.
Finally,
마지막으로,
we've reached our happy ending.
우리는 해피엔딩에 도달했습니다.
Wait.
잠깐만요.
Let's change the music.
음악을 바꾸자.
Because our ending will be a perfectly happy one.
우리의 결말이니까 정말 행복할 것 같아요.
CAN THIS LOVE BE TRANSLATED?
이 사랑을 번역할 수 있나요?
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi
자막 번역: 최지민